The end of an empire. The birth of two nations.
Viceroy's House is a drama, history film directed by Gurinder Chadha.
In 1947, Lord Mountbatten assumes the post of last Viceroy, charged with handing India back to its people, living upstairs at
the house which was the home of British rulers, whilst 500 Hindu, Muslim and Sikh servants lived downstairs.
Lord Mountbatten, played by Hugh Bonneville.
Edwina Mountbatten, played by Gillian Anderson.
General Hastings Ismay, played by Michael Gambon.
Jeet, played by Manish Dayal.
Aalia, played by Huma Qureshi.
Ewart, played by David Hayman.
Viceroy's House is a 2017 historical drama film directed by Gurinder Chadha
and written by Paul Mayeda Berges, Moira Buffini, and Chadha.
The film stars Hugh Bonneville, Gillian Anderson, Manish
Dayal, Huma Qureshi, and Michael Gambon.
It was selected to be screened out of competition at the
67th Berlin International Film Festival.
The film was released in the United Kingdom on 3 March 2017, while the Hindi dubbed version titled
Partition: 1947 was released in India on 18 August 2017, three days after its 70th Independence Day.
It was released worldwide on 1 September 2017.
Viceroy's House is based on Freedom at Midnight by Larry Collins and Dominique Lapierre, and The
Shadow of the Great Game: The Untold Story of Partition by Narendra Singh Sarila.
The film explores themes of independence, religious
conflict, colonial india, interfaith love.
The tone is emotional.